I spent the last two years listening to
and reading Jordan Peterson's stuff
uh-huh
oh yeah we love Jordan like I think he's
great and yet at the same time it is
true that I have a nagging sense that
there's something let's say regressive
in his view of the individual well if
you're gonna be a sovereign individual
gonna be swept away anyway about dated
so but it doesn't get did it so he
doesn't get that okay Jordan is a
brilliant teacher he's a brilliant
psychologist he's a brilliant art
historian credit valuable before Jordan
that was Camille Paglia she's Eve
anything even better she's done the same
thing for 30 years she just happened to
be a woman so the guys didn't listen to
her her sexual persona and Jordans maps
of meaning a brilliant books but they're
written by historians about mythologies
and things that's great okay you start
there so if you want to learn Freud if
you want to learn dune anywhere learn
Nietzsche Jordan Peters is the best
teacher you can have it doesn't mean
however that he had east an expert on
the future he doesn't get did it'll
he happens to be YouTube phenomenon just
because it happens to be neutral when
you put him in a YouTube studio that's
exactly why he's so successful but it
doesn't get digital he's stuck using it
up in his Twitter account he's not
really using anything like that
oh that's exactly when when these guys
who have their lives transformed by
Europeans because it's basically just
kicking their asses to get up in the
morning make your bed and get your shit
together which any man should you at
least if you want women okay you have to
do that that's just basics you know
common sense butter when these guys can
calm Jordan they ask him for advice
about their own future they're asking a
58 year old nerd who you know he's
married to his childhood sweetheart and
I lived in the Canadian countryside most
of his life he's not gonna he's not
gonna tell him to go to Burning Man or
oh no no he doesn't live in Stockholm he
doesn't live in London or Paris like you
and I do and he doesn't have tender on
his pocket he doesn't have access to all
the world's information he doesn't have
apps that there's a 600 persons within
four blocks what do you want to start
you know none of that existent is even
its imagination he's not even there okay
so when he gives you advice it's all I
call you should move the Canadian
countries I didn't get a wife and stay
with her no matter what that's not gonna
happen Jordan and you know it it's not
gonna happen
these guys who you take advice from
Jordan Peters are gonna be terribly
disappointed cuz they're not gonna live
that you wanna be doesn't I start so I'm
not sure I'm not sure if I fully agree
with that what cuz I don't think there's
that many people who go to Burning Man
but there's a lot of people in Middle
America who will listen to Jordan
Pederson and probably I mean but you're
you're looking at you're looking at a
sort of elite bunch of people and it's
covered 10 years now you should have
otherwise who are damn loser I'm talking
about what we're heading I'm Marx I'm
Nietzsche I'm not talking about the lump
and proletariat to sit on the fat ass
and watch TV shows on the line I don't
care if I focus on then I'm gonna give
you all the wrong answers I'm trying to
answer where we're going what you should
do Jordan does not and the reason why
Jordan Peterson doesn't because he's
fundamentally flawed
he's ideology he's an American
individualist and he's an ironic
Christian that's two negatives right
there he wants you to believe in
Christianity although you don't believe
in Christ how the fuck is that going to
work he's like saying that you were
gonna have the building left you're
gonna have the walls in the beautiful
roof but the basement is rotten well if
the basements wrong in the house gonna
fall apart surely not sustainable Jordan
you may wish that will work if you read
the death of God and needs he understood
you cannot build buildings on false
basements so don't do that and where is
the other part of this it's this damn
religion called American individualism
and it starts at the carton 16:32 human
beings are not individuals we are tribal
we get our identity from tribal we get
our identity from relationships Andrew
and Alexandra do not exist what exists
is a dialogue between under an Alexander
right here I can't you have both can you
have individual no no you know you're
Andrew is nothing but a byproduct of the
relationships you're involved with yours
answer self only occurs when you have a
problem you can't solve you have a pass
on it yeah but you i'll exhibit earn it
I mean you're an individual I mean
you're no no I'm not an individual in
some sense you're I mean no Christ died
the little on the cross and you returned
in little three days late no he died on
a cross and never returned
well I've been sitting here Buddism for
years so I understand that you know
we're not selves in that sense but yeah
but but we're still you know there's
still something important no no okay no
no what's important is to drive we hate
being individuals what's true in being
an individual is sort of a lonely state
right it's the guys who come to Jordan
Peters and orders purpose he tells them
purpose is the most important thing in
your life he doesn't give them the
purpose he just tells them they need to
go and find him okay I'm a philosopher I
have to work with purpose I'd give you
the purpose is to find your tribe and
find your archetype if your role within
the tribe and an older mentor is your
archetype I can guide you so you can
become brilliant and what you should do
so you can contribute your tribe be
proud of yourself that's the only sense
of self okay that's great you know it's
completely tribal it's in the relation
with the tribe you get any value you may
have no value whatsoever outside of the
tribal context you're not on a market
you're not selling yourself you know
you're not applying for for welfare
state funding or anything like that all
you are tribal you create value within
the tribe that's how you get meaning and
purpose in your life it has nothing to
do with religion it's everything to do
with tribe then we create religion based
on that because religion is the
storytelling on how you keep the tribe
together and how you put the tribe on
the moon we've bent God's asked the
parents of our parents you listed the
old father is the original paternal God
the old modest original maternal God who
are they the or father is the patriarch
of the patchwork you
motor is the matric of the metric so
that we are responsible to the match our
competitor and follow their damn orders
for own survival and trust them that's
exactly what we have related the system
would beyond beyond over there East God
he's already where we're heading and
that's because I was I was to go with
her right
I always thought the god principle was
was the origin you know what's your kind
of saying the opposite you're saying the
opposite of how we think of God like
normally we think of God is the origin
of everything right no we didn't well if
Yuri but I mean even even the Bible
doesn't say God created the earth
created the world the Bible start God
created order out of chaos
yeah that's up crating toward the case
was there already even in the Bible the
universe creates itself but to make
order of it which is finding fellows ah
to create order out of it to create a
story that makes sense
ah ok no it makes us now I know what
it's all about
it's also being some deep thinking right
yeah yeah what so we create gods that's
what you're saying we create God and we
create gods and and this is a creative
activity that where we participate in
it's not like just just we're possibly
created by some but that's that's why by
something and and we have to bow down to
that it's it's like we are we are
participants and you know in the we're
created by a nature and we want to
belong to whatever we came from the
first reaction we have we're born is you
want to get back in you want to die
yeah hey we can't so we're forced to
think that we want to live and then we
get a taste for it then we suck at it
for another year anyway so we kind of
you know we're not on our own but
completely taken care of the first year
the tip services we have no idea where
that milk comes from its magical but
yeah we get it
and maybe the false religious the false
religious view is assertiveness dalchi
for that tip as you're saying but well
so Astron ism isn't Taoism isn't
Buddhism isn't hmm that's why I went to
the East while I went to these was that
the fundamental religious we have in the
West all the Arabic religions are all
based in the deal
gonna get to paradise one day but you're
gonna get back into the womb no I've
been to the wound already I'd done that
I'd leave them more a fine tent for nine
months yeah sure was nice but I wouldn't
take opiates two days I've wanted to be
there again I don't I won't have a
little bit I want to be alive I want to
be passionate about things I want to do
philosophy I won't have a full life I
want to be a full human being and I want
to die happy having lived a full life I
won't hold us I don't want to be in a
more front end I find stupid and
degrading from us growing up I'm no
longer a child okay so you left that
behind
now the problem with religions that say
you're the child of God you should think
it can be child again and be responsible
whatever you do you're getting
forgiveness that's a really good sell
for lazy people yeah well I never got
that that's Islam for you they're all in
that together so so rested ISM stood for
something different he was the opposite
so Astron ism celebrated the tree of
knowledge it celebrated human
independence from the gods it celebrated
being adult being independent from your
parents moving on creating a new world
different from your parents world okay
so the East is fundamentally what I call
the Silk Route tried the Silk Route is
still unwritten history and why because
the circle connected China with Persia
and India these are the three empires of
the East have lasted for thousands of
years massive cultures because India is
essentially the plains of northern India
and also southern India and you can
house 1.5 billion people there today
John now essentially you to River
Valley's ready to go to China the
striking thing is that they got the
climate of the Mediterranean but got the
Earth's of northern Europe well you know
it's like the best you can get America
certainly has seen you get to China just
like yeah this is the place where you
could have one and a half or two billion
people absolutely you've got all the
resources you need you trivia Valley
stuff like that you can read these huge
cultures between China and India was
Persia and Persia was a huge culture
that expanded territorially through
ideology great ideas and through
military exercise right so the Persians
created the first Universal Empire we're
gonna study universalism today and
solid ISM that starts 600 before Christ
with the Persian conquest of Babylon the
purchase beat the Babylonians wanna
Empire conquer the other but the first
thing that happens the Kouros arise in
Babylon is that walks into the temple of
Marduk and kisses marks feet meaning he
missed most clever shamanic move ever
done his true shame and his king he
walks into the temple of the enemy and
kisses the enemies God's feet meaning
were united mm-hmm religion philosophy
politics military United it's just one
Federation and then he sets the Jews
free and they can leave Babylon and they
can walk back to rusyn and create the
first proper nation and the nation is
then within the Empire we can learn
enormous Lee from this day we can learn
enormous about Babylon and Jerusalem
acted collaborating the Babylon to me is
the name of the world as a city Babylon
is the name of Digital Jerusalem is the
name of nationalisms the name a mass
media society the Industrial Age of
capitalism or nationalism of individuals
and everything we practice last three or
four hundred years can be summarized as
Jerusalem and everything and moving
towards no which is the true Imperial
state and between Jerusalem Babylon we
have to make comparative studies how are
these two cities different how are these
two environments different how can they
collaborate how can we keep Jerusalem to
remember what nations are like when
nations are strong and deliver and what
does it mean to create a truly Imperial
Society that captures the whole globe
and what we have to use the machines to
train people to love the stranger if
machine intelligence gonna do one thing
train people of the church enable us to
love the stranger it's gonna be the most
difficult thing we're gonna have to do
the next 100 years or otherwise the
machines will get rid of us mm-hmm
that's very interesting
yeah yeah that's the big scope who did
it yeah we wrote a book called the globe
because there can't be really strangers
I mean I mean we are okay Andrew you and
our shamanic
we're different we don't care about skin
color
people don't know I know yeah that's
right yeah I expose you so since they do
and they're they're the material we're
gonna work with we have to be respectful
how they operate and listen to them and
take that in yeah what else carry on
become resource and then we gonna kill
them all right you either work people
and you train their self-confidence or
you just kill them you don't have any
third option that's what education is so
today yeah we need the damn shames we
need them so bad because we wrote a book
called the global Empire fifteen years
ago
20 30 20 2003 that was the global and by
the second books Atticus not wrote and
we said you said the global Empire that
is already here it's called the Internet
the Internet Protocol is a global
Imperial code mm-hmm let the rest the
world has to follow you cannot opt out
of the internet that's impossible
it's just conquer the globe and
essentially the world today is one thing
called Internet - it's seven billion
very confused dividual bodies are
connected mm-hmm these bodies are gonna
be around a generation from now they
better have some kind of contributed
role for the overall system meaning what
does it mean to be human in digital
well it means supplying something
machines cannot do they cannot be
biologically and emotionally intelligent
so this is kind of the opposite of the
the kurtzweil vision the singularity has
already happened seven billion people
are too
connected with each other as we speak
nobody has opted out
nobody can opt out mm-hmm if you're
gonna if you're gonna do Internet
addiction work the way to do it is you
open you start a damn Facebook group for
internet addicts you can't believe the
meaning the mediums conquered everything
it's conquered our entire imaginary
realm it's imaginary the even truth
production everything that has value to
us has been conquered by digital already
we call it the global Empire we wrote
the book sixteen years ago we said it's
already happened it's a fact now I have
to live with that fact the Internet is
not confused he just operates it
operates in a way that while neutron
bombs can kill humanity we cannot kill
the internet with the neutron bombs can
okay we can't we couldn't have some sort
of explosion that would know you can
blow an entire planet the internet will
still be around how does that how would
that would that would that work he was
build by military engineers to survive
any years and they were successful and
they created the monster okay
now the monsters out of the bottle it is
a monster yep again what do you want
from me mister what do you want from me
that's the honest question today and my
answer to that is synthetic intelligence
synthetic intelligence yeah my friends
in America for example you know Jordy
Hall that's working collective
intelligence okay that's another term I
call it synthetic in charge because what
it is it is that we're looking at life
and we're looking at consciousness and
we're looking at sub consciousness and
we're looking at how the human body
operates and how the human mind operates
how the senses operate we have to
relearn we have to we study Aristotle
have to go back to basics again to
understand what it means to be human